# **Chelsey Machin**

# Full-Stack Software Developer

Multi-talented full-stack developer with an early background in social work and youth services delivery. Self-starting career switcher that will have two full degrees under my belt by 28. Incredibly motivated to learn and grow through any means available. Professional experience with client and server-side application development within an Agile framework on a remote, distributed team. In my current role, I'm using Vue.JS as my main front-end framework and a pretty old back-end that's industry custom and based on a multi-valued data system. In my personal development, I'm playing with React, Java, Python, and a bunch of other stuff in between! Please peek at my GitHub or portfolio for current personal projects and schoolwork.

### Contact

#### **Address**

Tacoma, WA, 98406

#### Phone

(360) 979-7099

chelseymachin@gmail.com

GitHub LinkedIn

Portfolio

# **Skills**

- JavaScript / Vue / React
- o C++ / Java / Python
- GIT / Bash / PowerShell
- Jira & general ticketing
- MySQL / Postgres
- Adobe Design Suite
- o ZenDesk Slack Teams
- Microsoft Office suite
- Technical documentation
- Automated testing (Mocha & Jest)
- CMS Administration

## **Education**

#### **University of Washington**

Bachelor of Arts in Social Welfare

#### **Western Governor's University**

Graduation Date: July 2022

# **Work History**

#### January 2022 - Current

#### Full Stack Software Development Engineer I (Remote)

Burkhart Dental Supply - Tacoma, WA

- o Utilize Jira and Azure DevOps to follow Agile development methodology
- o Develop responsive client-side interfaces and server-side applications in support of business needs
- o Engage with internal clients and team members about technical best practices and optimal solutions
- o Participate in monitoring and developing internal technical guidance and professional development
- o Stay up to date on industry trends, particularly with accessibility, usability, and emerging technology

#### July 2021 - December 2021

#### **Software Developer Intern (Remote)**

Burkhart Dental Supply - Tacoma, WA

- o Assist the development team with all aspects of software design
- o Attend and contribute to company development meetings
- o Learn the codebase and improving coding skills
- o Write and maintain code
- o Work on minor bug fixes
- o Monitor the technical performance of internal systems
- o Gather information from users about program functionality
- o Conduct development tests

#### November 2020 - July 2021

#### **IT Help Desk**

Burkhart Dental Supply - Tacoma, WA

- o SME for all business applications; first point of contact for all IT inquiries
- o Initial troubleshooting for database, server, site, and hardware functionality
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science o Develop and manage interdepartmental tickets (Development tickets, Marketing tickets, etc.)
  - Maintain Active Directory, mail permissions, and application permissions for 400+ employees